<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>regenerative agriculture on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</title>
    <link>https://knozue.github.io/categories/regenerative-agriculture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in regenerative agriculture on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://knozue.github.io/categories/regenerative-agriculture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Remote sensing 1.1: python -&gt; Webhooks -&gt; Google Sheet</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2024/12/01/remote-sensing-1-1-python-webhooks-google-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2024/12/01/remote-sensing-1-1-python-webhooks-google-sheet/</guid>
      <description>Toward my goal for remote sensing of my yard soil, I would like to divide its porject into several modules.  module 1. Automatically recording data in Google Sheet (from my computer to Google Sheet). module 2. Sensing soil data using Raspberry pi 3 model B. module 3. Combining 1 and 2   Setting up module 1 Since my Rasppberry pi 3 model 3 runs under Python, I would like to use Python in my computer to send some data to Google Sheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regenerative agriculture 3: my backyard trial</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2024/11/25/regenerative-agriculture-3-my-backyard-trial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2024/11/25/regenerative-agriculture-3-my-backyard-trial/</guid>
      <description>Regenerative Agriculture in my backyard I decided to test regenerative agriculture in my backyard, comparing two different crop plant mixes: California native plants vs California Habit Mix, following principals described in Helen Atthowe and Gave Brown.
 step 1. Remove all plants in designated area (two of 1 m x 1.5 m) and dug out 30 cm. step 2. Sprinkle thin layers of dried rabbit poops (kept in a compost bin at least for two weeks), which has no more ammonium smell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regenerative Agriculture 2</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2023/12/25/regenerative-agriculture-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2023/12/25/regenerative-agriculture-2/</guid>
      <description>More learning on Regenerative Agriculture I have to mention an important book published this summer on regenerative agriculture, written by Helen Atthowe. titled The Ecological Farm. From a my favorite podcast on regenerative agriculture, called “Regenerative Agriculture Podcast” by John Kemp, host John Kemp interviewed Helen in the July 6th episode. I learned that Helen has been practicing regenerative agriculture for years in her three farms. In this episode I was so impressed that Helen’s way of regenerating soil uses living plant mulch instead of animal manure, which is suitable to small farms in Japan (I think).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>リジェネラティブ農業 1</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2023/01/29/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2023/01/29/1/</guid>
      <description>サステナブル農業である、リジェネラティブ農業を追求すべきなのか？ 環境再生型（リジェネラティブ）農業（またはカーボンファーミング）は自分がが今</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regenerative Agriculture 1</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2023/01/28/regenerative-agriculture-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2023/01/28/regenerative-agriculture-1/</guid>
      <description>Regenerative Agriculture, sustainable firming we should pursue? Regenerative agriculture (or Carbon farming) is what I’ve been looking for. I remember that I read “The One-Straw Revolution: An Introduction to Natural Farming” by Masanobu Fukuoka (in Japanse) many times in a university library when I was undergraduate student (35 years ago!). Since then I’ve been working on plant molecular biology, stepping on data science those days. The last year my favorite news podcast handled the regerative agriculture, which lead me to read “Dirt to Soil” (Gabe Brown), who were practicing regenerative agriculture 20 years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
