<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>California on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</title>
    <link>https://knozue.github.io/tags/california.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in California on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://knozue.github.io/tags/california/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Six months later: Native plant garden project 3</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/04/17/six-months-later-native-plant-garden-project3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/04/17/six-months-later-native-plant-garden-project3.html</guid>
      <description>Beautiful lupines blooming in my yard! April 2019 lunine blooming
 Native plants have been growing and growing in my yards. In this early spring, lots of lupine plants have been bloomed that has As I reported in Jan 16, 2019, our yards have nave lupine plants from native plant seeds packat. Surprisingly lots of lupine plants grew bigger and had lots of beautiful violet flowers.
 What is this plant?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Needs more cargo space in electric vehicles!</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/03/30/needs-more-cargo-space-in-electric-vehicles.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/03/30/needs-more-cargo-space-in-electric-vehicles.html</guid>
      <description>Advantages of electric vehicles Electric vehicle (EV) became popular in California. Recently I can find more than one Tesla car during my daily commute. There are a couple of advantages of EV compared with gas powered vehicles; (1) higher cost efficiency (higher MPGe1), (2) lower maintainance cost, and (3) tax incentives and rebate (read an article in energysage.com, one in a utility company, and a site from U.S. Department of Energy).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three months later: Native plant garden project2</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/01/16/three-months-later-native-plant-garden-project2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/01/16/three-months-later-native-plant-garden-project2.html</guid>
      <description>Many small plants are growing in my yards. Are they native plants that I sprindkled? As I posted in last fall, I started watering early November 2018 and late rainy season has started after the tragic wild fire (&amp;ldquo;Butte Camp Fire&amp;rdquo;). On January 2019 I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a couple of unfamiliar plants in my yards (Fig. 1), which should be one of native plants in California central valley pollination seed mix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native plant garden project</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/18/native-plant-garden-project.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/18/native-plant-garden-project.html</guid>
      <description>Why don&amp;rsquo;t you grow local native plants in your yards? Lawn in yards are common in USA. However, keeping lawn green needs lots of water in California. California central valley is a center of agriculture due to excellent soil quality (ref). However, weather of California central valley is Mediteranian type, which has long dry summer and wet winter (ref). Recent years California has frequent drought problems (ref), which leads me to try replacing lawn into drought resistant plants, especially local native plants, which are resistant to drought.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>