<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</title>
    <link>https://knozue.github.io/post.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://knozue.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of team rank prediction in sports league by sum of residuals</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/12/29/evaluation-of-team-rank-prediction-in-sports-league-by-sum-of-residuals.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/12/29/evaluation-of-team-rank-prediction-in-sports-league-by-sum-of-residuals.html</guid>
      <description>Evaluation of team rank prediction in sports league by sum of residuals J1_2019_pred_results&amp;lt;-read_csv(file.path(&amp;quot;2019-12-</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charging an electric vehicle at home: 240V outlet installation in my garage</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/12/27/charging-an-electric-vehicle-at-home-240v-outlet-installation-in-my-garage.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/12/27/charging-an-electric-vehicle-at-home-240v-outlet-installation-in-my-garage.html</guid>
      <description>Charging an electric vehicle at home Fig 1. Two 240V outlet installed in my garage today!
The world of charging an electric vehicle is totally different from gas-fueling an gasoline-powered vehicle. Similar to gas stations there are growing number of electric charger stations, such as Tesla Superchargers and EVgo. The biggest difference is that your can charge your electric vehicle at home. An easy ways is to use regular 110V outlet in your garage, which is called level 1 charging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decarbonization project: switching a gas-powered vehicle into an electric vehicle (EV)</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/12/05/decarbonization-project-switching-a-gas-powered-vehicle-into-an-electric-vehicle-ev.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/12/05/decarbonization-project-switching-a-gas-powered-vehicle-into-an-electric-vehicle-ev.html</guid>
      <description>Decarbonization and carbon sequestration  The U. S. officially notified withdrawal from the Paris Agreement on Nov 4, 2019. I am so sad to hear the news that movement toward decarbonization is essential to prevent from global warming. Please listen a high-school student (Greta Thunberg) speech on decarbonization at United Nations’ Climate Action Summit in September 2019. We should start working on decarbonization ASAP. Toward big goals of decarbonization in the world, our family started from carbon capture/sequestration project, “native plant project”, which also saved lots of precious water in California.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>脱炭素化プロジェクト: ガソリン車から電気自動車へ</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/12/03/decarbonization1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/12/03/decarbonization1.html</guid>
      <description>脱炭素化(decarbonization)と炭素回収(carbon sequestration) 2015年のパリ議定書や 1人の高校生環境活動家グレタ・トゥーンベリさんの</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eight months later: Native plant project 6</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/06/10/eight-months-later-native-plant-project-6.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/06/10/eight-months-later-native-plant-project-6.html</guid>
      <description>Milkweed has come back! Milkweed is one of California native plants. This spring milkweed plants returned in my backyard exactly at the same location (Fig.1), suggesting they are perennials. Milkweed plants are very important because they are the only food for precious migrating butterfly, Monarch butterfly (please read an artible in National Geographic). For most organisms milkweed is toxic because their body contain several glucosidic substances called cardenolides. Why the glucosidic substances are not toxic to Monahch butterfly?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>コミュニケーションの極意：NHK for School お伝と伝次郎</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/05/11/otsuta-to-denjiro.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/05/11/otsuta-to-denjiro.html</guid>
      <description>「お伝と伝次郎」：大人にこそ役立つNHK for schoolの番組！ 海外在住の子供の日本語教育にはNHK for schoolというウェブサイトは大変役に</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven months later: Native plant garden project 5</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/05/10/seven-months-later-native-plant-garden-project-5.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/05/10/seven-months-later-native-plant-garden-project-5.html</guid>
      <description>Blooming of Clarkia williamsonii; Farewell to spring? After blooming, lupine have lots of been-like seed pods (Fig. 1).
Fig. 2. Clarkia williamsonii blooming
 Among Clarkia unguiculata plants, Clarkia williamsonii started blooming (Fig. 2) . One of closely related species, Clarkia amoena, is called farewell to spring. So as it is May, blooming of Clarkia williamsonii is likely the sign of short spring and beginning of long dry season in California.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven months later: Native plant garden project4</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/05/07/seven-months-later-native-plant-garden-project4.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/05/07/seven-months-later-native-plant-garden-project4.html</guid>
      <description> Clarkia unguiculata has started blooming Clarkia unguiculata blooming
 Fig.2. Close up
 As I posted in January, I have lots of Clarkia unguiculata plants, which start blooming the last week in April. Although it seems become early dry season, plants in my yards are still green.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six months later: Native plant garden project 3</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/04/17/six-months-later-native-plant-garden-project3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/04/17/six-months-later-native-plant-garden-project3.html</guid>
      <description>Beautiful lupines blooming in my yard! April 2019 lunine blooming
 Native plants have been growing and growing in my yards. In this early spring, lots of lupine plants have been bloomed. As I reported in Jan 16, 2019, our yards have lupine plants from native plant seeds mix. Surprisingly lots of lupine plants grew bigger and had lots of beautiful violet flowers.
 What is this plant? unknown flower</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Needs more cargo space in electric vehicles!</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/03/30/needs-more-cargo-space-in-electric-vehicles.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/03/30/needs-more-cargo-space-in-electric-vehicles.html</guid>
      <description>Advantages of electric vehicles Electric vehicle (EV) became popular in California. Recently I can find more than one Tesla car during my daily commute. There are a couple of advantages of EV compared with gas powered vehicles; (1) higher cost efficiency (higher MPGe1), (2) lower maintainance cost, and (3) tax incentives and rebate (read an article in energysage.com, one in a utility company, and a site from U.S. Department of Energy).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slide presentation in R with xarigan package</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/01/30/slide-presentation-in-r-with-xarigan-package.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/01/30/slide-presentation-in-r-with-xarigan-package.html</guid>
      <description>How to make slides in RStudio As an audience of a seminar, it is difficut to follow presentation when screen is scrolling down that happens in regular websites. Esay convertion from RMarkdown to slides are described in Rmarkdown book. To make slides for presentation of your RMarkdown documents, xarigan package developed by Yihui Xie is a powerful tool. Please find a demo presentation. Alternative method is using Rpresentation or isoslides (see details in the Rmarkdown book).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three months later: Native plant garden project2</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/01/16/three-months-later-native-plant-garden-project2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/01/16/three-months-later-native-plant-garden-project2.html</guid>
      <description>Many small plants are growing in my yards. Are they native plants that I sprindkled? As I posted in last fall, I started watering early November 2018 and late rainy season has started after the tragic wild fire (&amp;ldquo;Butte Camp Fire&amp;rdquo;). On January 2019 I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a couple of unfamiliar plants in my yards (Fig. 1), which should be one of native plants in California central valley pollination seed mix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confirming genotypes by visualizing mutations from RNAseq data</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/01/08/confirming-genotype-by-visualizing-mutation-in-rnaseq-data.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/01/08/confirming-genotype-by-visualizing-mutation-in-rnaseq-data.html</guid>
      <description>RNAseq is a powerful tool for transcriptome analysis. It is also useful for genotyping (for example, 1). Here I demonstrated an example of confirmation of genotype used for RNAseq. There are some unavoidable errors due to unexpected mistakes in many steps (eg. contamination of seeds, contamination of samples, pipetting errors during library preparation, rotation of plates, etc.). Therefore confirmation of genotype using RNAseq data is useful for quality control of samples used 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VennDiagram with differentially expressed genes</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/12/28/venndiagram-with-differentially-expressed-genes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/12/28/venndiagram-with-differentially-expressed-genes.html</guid>
      <description>How to draw VennDiagram from differentially expressed genes? The last time I posted how to draw a VennDiagram with a simulated data. This time I would like to explain how to draw a VennDiagram from differentially expressed genes (DEGs).
 Overlap between DEGs from Oct 1, 2018 blog post, “Differential expression analysis with public available sequencing data” library(limma) library(tidyverse) ## ── Attaching packages ───────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────── tidyverse 1.2.1 ── ## ✔ ggplot2 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List to data frame in R tidyverse</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/12/20/list-to-data-frame-in-r-tidyverse.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/12/20/list-to-data-frame-in-r-tidyverse.html</guid>
      <description>Converting list object to a data frame object is common in R. There are many ways and here is another way using tidyverse packages.
bind_cols() This is an efficient implementation of the common pattern of do.call(rbind, dfs) or do.call(cbind, dfs) for binding many data frames into one (cited from tidyverse package site).
library(tidyverse) ## ── Attaching packages ─────────────────────────────────────────────────── tidyverse 1.2.1 ── ## ✔ ggplot2 3.1.0 ✔ purrr 0.2.5 ## ✔ tibble 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annotating sequences by benchling.com</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/12/06/annotating-sequences-by-benchling-com.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/12/06/annotating-sequences-by-benchling-com.html</guid>
      <description>Annotating sequences is critical for making a construct in molecular biology. Benchling.com is a powerful tool for automating the annotation process. This example explains how to label “2x35S promoter” region in sequences of interest. step1: Before adding 2x35S promoter benchling.com plasmid annotation (step1) step2: Exporting 2x25S promoter feature info (sequences) from known annotated sequence From pMDC32 vector</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive app for time-course data of your kids&#39; meet scores</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/11/06/interactive-app-for-time-course-data-of-your-kids-meet-scores.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/11/06/interactive-app-for-time-course-data-of-your-kids-meet-scores.html</guid>
      <description>Shiny package in R language can create a fantastic application in interactive mode using a browser (for free!). In an example below, you can download data file for four years of figure records in US junior olympics of synchronized swimming (public available data from USA synchro web site, compiled by Kazu Nozue). Using search box, you can narrow data down using any words found in any columns in data, such</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another plant defense hormone is required for responses to light in plant</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/26/another-plant-defense-hormone-is-required-for-responses-to-light-in-plant.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/26/another-plant-defense-hormone-is-required-for-responses-to-light-in-plant.html</guid>
      <description>Plants use light as energy source as well as signals for environmental signal changes. Under the canopy shade phtosynthesis activity is reduced, therefore plants responded to existance of neighboring plants that causes near future crisis, such as growing taller and flowering earlier to produce seeds as early as possible, which are collectivcey known as shade avoidance responses. This week I published my paper titled &amp;ldquo;Network analysis reveals a role for salicylic acid pathway components in shade avoidance&amp;rdquo; in Plant Physiology, an international journal in plant biology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DGE clustering with ggplot2</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/24/dge-clustering-with-ggplot2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/24/dge-clustering-with-ggplot2.html</guid>
      <description>Hierarchical clustering is powerful method to classify gene expression pattern. Here I applied a method develped by an example of plotly.
Required libraries # install.packages(&amp;#39;ggdendro&amp;#39;) library(tidyverse);library(ggdendro);library(plotly)  Reading expression value # reading gene expression value (Ding, 2018) from my privious blog ([&amp;quot;Differential expression analysis with public available sequencing data&amp;quot;](https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/01/differential-expression-analysis-with-public-available-sequencing-data.html) on 2018-10-01)) load(file.path(&amp;quot;2018-10-24-dge-clustering-with-ggplot2_files&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;dge.nolow.Ding2018.Rdata&amp;quot;)) dge.nolow ## Loading required package: edgeR ## Loading required package: limma ## An object of class &amp;quot;DGEList&amp;quot; ## $counts ## SRR6739807 SRR6739808 SRR6739809 SRR6739810 SRR6739811 SRR6739812 ## 1 3598.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native plant garden project</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/18/native-plant-garden-project.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/18/native-plant-garden-project.html</guid>
      <description>Why don&amp;rsquo;t you grow local native plants in your yards? Lawn in yards are common in USA. However, keeping lawn green needs lots of water in California. California central valley is a center of agriculture due to excellent soil quality (ref). However, weather of California central valley is Mediteranian type, which has long dry summer and wet winter (ref). Recent years California has frequent drought problems (ref), which leads me to try replacing lawn into drought resistant plants, especially local native plants, which are resistant to drought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over-representation analysis 3: GOseq with GO term in non-model organisms</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/17/over-representation-analysis-3-goseq-with-non-model-go-term.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/17/over-representation-analysis-3-goseq-with-non-model-go-term.html</guid>
      <description>If you want to analyze non-model organisms, what you can do? Please prepare
fasta file for cDNA of your species (eg. Brassica rapa), fasta file for cDNA of a close model organisms to your species (eg. Arabidopsis thaliana for Brassica rapa), blastn program installed in your computer (UNIX (or Mac OSX) or LINUX) (detailed instruciton from NCBI)    required libraries library(tidyverse);library(readr);library(readxl) ## ── Attaching packages ───────────────────────────────────── tidyverse 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merging two branches in Git </title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/12/merging-two-branches-in-git.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/12/merging-two-branches-in-git.html</guid>
      <description>Do you have branches in your git and want to merge them? How to merge two branches? Here is a simple example using RStudio.
 Initial commit. (&amp;ldquo;1st commit&amp;rdquo;)
 2nd commit (&amp;ldquo;koi no yokan&amp;rdquo;)
 3rd commit (&amp;ldquo;Tsuki ni nureta futari&amp;rdquo;)
 4th commit (&amp;ldquo;Mayonaka Sugi no koi&amp;rdquo;)
 Making branch1
 Commit on branch1 (&amp;ldquo;Jirettai&amp;rdquo;)
 Move to master and 5th commit on 1st line (&amp;ldquo;Wine red&amp;rdquo;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over-representation analysis 2: GOseq using custom categories</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/10/over-representation-analysis-2-goseq-using-custom-categories.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/10/over-representation-analysis-2-goseq-using-custom-categories.html</guid>
      <description>Download updated gene description (copied from “2018-10-01-…Rmd”) Most updated annotation can be downloaded from TAIR website (for subscribers). I used “TAIR Data 20180630”.
library(tidyverse);library(readxl);library(readr) ## ── Attaching packages ───────────────────────────────────── tidyverse 1.2.1 ── ## ✔ ggplot2 3.1.0 ✔ purrr 0.2.5 ## ✔ tibble 1.4.2 ✔ dplyr 0.7.7 ## ✔ tidyr 0.8.2 ✔ stringr 1.3.1 ## ✔ readr 1.1.1 ✔ forcats 0.3.0 ## ── Conflicts ──────────────────────────────────────── tidyverse_conflicts() ── ## ✖ dplyr::filter() masks stats::filter() ## ✖ dplyr::lag() masks stats::lag() # turn on TAIR subsciption before this procedure At.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over-representation analysis 5: useful tools</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/07/over-representation-analysis-5-useful-tools.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/07/over-representation-analysis-5-useful-tools.html</guid>
      <description>What genes were found in given categories (eg. GO term) in given gene list? library(tidyverse);library(readxl);library(readr) # prepare GO term - gene table (eg. GOSLIM result), gene list of interest, GO term of interest # output data format is a dataframe with columns (each GO term) and rows (gene names listed in gene list of interest provided by a user) and value (0 (absent) or 1 (present))  read GOseq result table eGOseqs&amp;lt;-list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differential expression analysis with public available sequencing data</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/01/differential-expression-analysis-with-public-available-sequencing-data.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/01/differential-expression-analysis-with-public-available-sequencing-data.html</guid>
      <description>Download this Rmd file Please download and modify your input/output file location
 Download RNA-seq data from NCBI Let’s use published RNA-seq data from Arabidopsis thaliana mutants (npr1-1 and npr4-4D) Ding (2018).
library(tidyverse) library(stringr) library(edgeR)  Trimming unnecessary sequences from data (such as adaptors) by trimmomatic  Needs to trim? Do fastqc and see results  trim? # working in directories containing fastq files fastfiles&amp;lt;-list.files(pattern=&amp;quot;fastq&amp;quot;) system(paste(&amp;quot;fastqc &amp;quot;,fastfiles,sep=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;)) # and then check reports to see if there are adaptor contamination # It seems those files were not contaminated so that no need to trim read files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over-representation analysis 4:  heatmap visualization</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/09/27/over-representation-analysis-4-heatmap-visualization.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/09/27/over-representation-analysis-4-heatmap-visualization.html</guid>
      <description>Insert Image&#34; to create directories for putting files-- Similar analysis was found in Guangchuang Yu bioconductor vignettes page.
library(tidyverse);library(ShortRead);library(goseq);library(GO.db);library(&amp;quot;annotate&amp;quot;) load GOseq function # download cDNA info directly from TAIR At_cdna&amp;lt;-Biostrings::readDNAStringSet(&amp;quot;https://www.arabidopsis.org/download_files/Sequences/TAIR10_blastsets/TAIR10_cds_20110103_representative_gene_model_updated&amp;quot;) At_cdna ## A DNAStringSet instance of length 27416 ## width seq names ## [1] 2016 ATGGTTCAATATAATTTCA...AAAACCGACAGGCGTTGA AT1G50920.1 | Sym... ## [2] 546 ATGACTCGTTTGTTGCCTT...GTTGATTCTGGTACATAG AT1G36960.1 | Sym... ## [3] 1734 ATGGATTCAGAGTCAGAGT...GATTATATTCTCCAATGA AT1G44020.1 | Sym... ## [4] 1059 ATGTCGGTTCCTCCTAGAT...AGAGAGAGTGATAAATAA AT1G15970.1 | Sym.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over-representation analysis 1: GOseq with GO terms in unsupported model organisms</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/09/26/over-representation-analysis-1-goseq-with-arabidopsis-go-term.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/09/26/over-representation-analysis-1-goseq-with-arabidopsis-go-term.html</guid>
      <description>purpose Over-representation analysis (“enrichment analysis”) of RNA-seq data considering cDNA length effects with unsupported model organisms.
 background Among many transcriptome analysis platforms, transcriptome analysis by next-generation sequencing (RNA-seq) has been used widely among model and non-model organisms. In RNA-seq, number of reads mapped to reference cDNA sequences (or genes in genome sequences) is proportional to size of genes1. This effect should be corrected especially when enrichment analysis is performed because a gene category of your interest is enriched only because genes in the category are large in size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make QRcode by R &#43; ggplot2</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/09/24/how-to-make-qrcode-by-r-ggplot2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/09/24/how-to-make-qrcode-by-r-ggplot2.html</guid>
      <description>ggplot2 version of qrcode generator library(qrcode) library(tidyverse) ## ── Attaching packages ───────────────────────────────────── tidyverse 1.2.1 ── ## ✔ ggplot2 3.1.0 ✔ purrr 0.2.5 ## ✔ tibble 1.4.2 ✔ dplyr 0.7.7 ## ✔ tidyr</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to read QR code and transfer data to Google sheet.</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/09/19/how-to-read-qr-code-and-transfer-data-to-google-sheet.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/09/19/how-to-read-qr-code-and-transfer-data-to-google-sheet.html</guid>
      <description>Copy scanned info by iphone and paste it on your computer software. Universal Clipboard is useful for this purpose when you use a certain model of iphone, Mac, and macOS.
 Step 1. Install barcode scanner app that can copy scanned info (“QR Scanner”, “QR Reader”, “Qrafter” from App Store worked as of Sep 2018). Step 2. Scan QR code (or any codes?) and copy decoded info. Step 3. Paste the decoded into into your software in your computer (eg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make QR code in Google Sheet using Integromat.com.</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/09/18/how-to-make-qr-code-in-google-sheet-using-integromat-com.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/09/18/how-to-make-qr-code-in-google-sheet-using-integromat-com.html</guid>
      <description>How to make QR code in google sheet using Integromat.com. The goal of this section is to create QRcode in Google Sheet
by using Intergromat.com1!
Outline Create Integromat.com account (free for 100 MB transfer and/or 1000 operation) Link Integromat.com account to your Google accout (for using Google Driv, Sheet) Create a new Google sheet with “sample”,“url”,“QRcode” columns. Create a new Scenario and run once to test it.   How to create QRcode generator scenario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>その実験、再現できなければ意味がない</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/09/18/%E3%81%9D%E3%81%AE%E5%AE%9F%E9%A8%93%E5%86%8D%E7%8F%BE%E3%81%A7%E3%81%8D%E3%81%AA%E3%81%91%E3%82%8C%E3%81%B0%E6%84%8F%E5%91%B3%E3%81%8C%E3%81%AA%E3%81%84.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/09/18/%E3%81%9D%E3%81%AE%E5%AE%9F%E9%A8%93%E5%86%8D%E7%8F%BE%E3%81%A7%E3%81%8D%E3%81%AA%E3%81%91%E3%82%8C%E3%81%B0%E6%84%8F%E5%91%B3%E3%81%8C%E3%81%AA%E3%81%84.html</guid>
      <description>再現できなければ意味がない 数年前、理化学研究所の研究者がNatureに発表した論文が元で1人の自殺者と多額のお金を使った再現性検証実験、多数</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>海外から日本への旅行：ポータブルWiFi ルーター or プリペイドSIMカード？</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/09/14/wifi-or-sim.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/09/14/wifi-or-sim.html</guid>
      <description>今年(2018年)は私には珍しく、単独で出張と家族旅行で日本へ二回行きました（米国在住です）。 双方とも地方での長旅の上に、大都市でも無料のW</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy dad needs project management skills!</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/09/12/the-first-post.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/09/12/the-first-post.html</guid>
      <description>Here I would like to start describe briefly how I manage my work and personal projects. How to make your experiments reproducible As scientists we need to convince others that your results are not by chance. Here are four advices I want to emphasize here. Keep all records on your lab notebook presicely that should be easy to understand. Simplify methods of data input to reduce errors. Have clear and</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>