<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>native-plant on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</title>
    <link>https://knozue.github.io/categories/native-plant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in native-plant on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://knozue.github.io/categories/native-plant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Regenerative agriculture 3: my backyard trial</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2024/11/25/regenerative-agriculture-3-my-backyard-trial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2024/11/25/regenerative-agriculture-3-my-backyard-trial/</guid>
      <description>Regenerative Agriculture in my backyard I decided to test regenerative agriculture in my backyard, comparing two different crop plant mixes: California native plants vs California Habit Mix, following principals described in Helen Atthowe and Gave Brown.
 step 1. Remove all plants in designated area (two of 1 m x 1.5 m) and dug out 30 cm. step 2. Sprinkle thin layers of dried rabbit poops (kept in a compost bin at least for two weeks), which has no more ammonium smell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native plant project v3 Fall 2023</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2023/12/26/native-plant-project-v3-fall-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2023/12/26/native-plant-project-v3-fall-2023/</guid>
      <description>Pomegranate fruits (Fig.1) Possibly due to plenty of rain last winter, we had bunch of Punica granatum fruites this year (Fig. 1). We learned waiting fruits with cracks outside resulted ripen and sweeter fruits.
 Sequestering carbon dioxide by many weeds this year (Fig.2) (Fig.3) (Fig.4)
The last growing season from late winter to spring we had lots of Thistle (Fig.2), Galium porrigens var. tenue (Graceful Bedstraw) (Fig. 3), and Vicia sativa (Fig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native plant project v2 2020-2021</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2021/10/06/native-plant-project-v2-2020-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2021/10/06/native-plant-project-v2-2020-2021/</guid>
      <description>2020 - 2021 landscape (frontyard) June 2020 Sep 2020 March 2021 May 2021 June 2021 Oct 5, 2021 Oct 21, 2021  Green and flowers during dry summer Grindelia_camporum stay green during summer (July 7, 2020).
Purple flowers of deseart willow (Chilopsis linearis desert willow) are beautiful (June 20, 20).
Blue flowers of Salvia x clevelandii ‘Pozo Blue’ Gray Musk Sage has been blooming (Date and picture).
Helianthus bolanderi Bolander’s sunflower (from my original 2018 Native plant seed mix).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native plant project v2 March-April 2020</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2020/04/18/native_plant_project_v2_march_april_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2020/04/18/native_plant_project_v2_march_april_2020/</guid>
      <description>March: Lupins started blooming and California poppies followed. March 21, 2020 This year Lupins and California poppies bloomed earlier than usual due to warm winter. During shelter-in place order many sidewalkers enjoyed our front yard. Some of them took pictures of plants, and others took California poppy plants and planted them to their front yards. As expected those plants were died. I would like to point out that taking s</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native plant garden project v2.1</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/12/30/native-plant-garden-project-v2-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/12/30/native-plant-garden-project-v2-1/</guid>
      <description>Upgrading my native plant garden Toward this rainy season I started upgrading my native plant gardens. Main goals of this project (v2) are
Completing removal of lawn from frontyard. Planting evergreen shrubs and perenials. Enlarging and remodeling backyard garden. Expanding grape tree in backyard. Labeling plants with weather resistant labeles.   Completing removal of lawn from frontyard. Fig.1 Survived lawn.
 Fig2. Replacing lawn to native plants.
 In the first project I expected spontanious disappearance of lawns from fronyard by no watering during summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eight months later: Native plant project 6</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/06/10/eight-months-later-native-plant-project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/06/10/eight-months-later-native-plant-project-6/</guid>
      <description>Milkweed has come back! Milkweed is one of California native plants. This spring milkweed plants returned in my backyard exactly at the same location (Fig.1), suggesting they are perennials. Milkweed plants are very important because they are the only food for precious migrating butterfly, Monarch butterfly (please read an artible in National Geographic). For most organisms milkweed is toxic because their body contain several glucosidic substances called cardenolides. Why the glucosidic substances are not toxic to Monahch butterfly?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven months later: Native plant garden project 5</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/05/10/seven-months-later-native-plant-garden-project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/05/10/seven-months-later-native-plant-garden-project-5/</guid>
      <description>Blooming of Clarkia williamsonii; Farewell to spring? After blooming, lupine have lots of been-like seed pods (Fig. 1).
Fig. 2. Clarkia williamsonii
 Among Clarkia unguiculata plants, Clarkia williamsonii started blooming (Fig. 2) . One of closely related species, Clarkia amoena, is called farewell to spring. So as it is May, blooming of Clarkia williamsonii is likely the sign of short spring and beginning of long dry season in California.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven months later: Native plant garden project4</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/05/07/seven-months-later-native-plant-garden-project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/05/07/seven-months-later-native-plant-garden-project4/</guid>
      <description> Clarkia unguiculata has started blooming Clarkia unguiculata
 Fig. 2. Close up
 As I posted in January, I have lots of Clarkia unguiculata plants, which start blooming the last week in April. Although it seems become early dry season, plants in my yards are still green.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six months later: Native plant garden project 3</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/04/17/six-months-later-native-plant-garden-project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/04/17/six-months-later-native-plant-garden-project-3/</guid>
      <description>Beautiful lupines blooming in my yard! April 2019 lupine blooming
 Native plants have been growing and growing in my yards. In this early spring, lots of lupine plants have been bloomed. As I reported in Jan 16, 2019, our yards have lupine plants from native plant seeds mix. Surprisingly lots of lupine plants grew bigger and had lots of beautiful violet flowers.
 What is this plant? unknown flower</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three months later: Native plant garden project2</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/01/16/three-monts-later-native-plant-garden-project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/01/16/three-monts-later-native-plant-garden-project2/</guid>
      <description>Many small plants are growing in my yards. Are they native plants that I sprindkled? Jan 7 2018 front yard plants
 As I posted in last fall, I started watering early November 2018 and late rainy season has started after the tragic wild fire (“Butte Camp Fire”). On January 2019 I’ve noticed a couple of unfamiliar plants in my yards (Fig. 1), which should be one of native plants in California central valley pollination seed mix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native plant garden project</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/18/native-plant-garden-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/18/native-plant-garden-project/</guid>
      <description>Why don&amp;rsquo;t you grow local native plants in your yards? Lawn in yards are common in USA. However, keeping lawn green needs lots of water in California. California central valley is a center of agriculture due to excellent soil quality (ref). However, weather of California central valley is Mediteranian type, which has long dry summer and wet winter (ref). Recent years California has frequent drought problems (ref), which leads me to try replacing lawn into drought resistant plants, especially local native plants, which are resistant to drought.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
