<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>native-plant on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</title>
    <link>/categories/native-plant.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in native-plant on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/native-plant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Eight months later: Native plant project 6</title>
      <link>/post/2019/06/10/eight-months-later-native-plant-project-6.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/06/10/eight-months-later-native-plant-project-6.html</guid>
      <description>Milkweed has come back! Milkweed is one of California native plants. This spring milkweed plants returned in my backyard exactly at the same location (Fig.1), suggesting they are perennials. Milkweed plants are very important because they are the only food for precious migrating butterfly, Monarch butterfly (please read an artible in National Geographic). For most organisms milkweed is toxic because their body contain several glucosidic substances called cardenolides. Why the glucosidic substances are not toxic to Monahch butterfly?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven months later: Native plant garden project 5</title>
      <link>/post/2019/05/10/seven-months-later-native-plant-garden-project-5.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/05/10/seven-months-later-native-plant-garden-project-5.html</guid>
      <description>Blooming of Clarkia williamsonii; Farewell to spring? After blooming, lupine have lots of been-like seed pods (Fig. 1).
Fig. 2. Clarkia williamsonii blooming
 Among Clarkia unguiculata plants, Clarkia williamsonii started blooming (Fig. 2) . One of closely related species, Clarkia amoena, is called farewell to spring. So as it is May, blooming of Clarkia williamsonii is likely the sign of short spring and beginning of long dry season in California.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven months later: Native plant garden project4</title>
      <link>/post/2019/05/07/seven-months-later-native-plant-garden-project4.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/05/07/seven-months-later-native-plant-garden-project4.html</guid>
      <description> Clarkia unguiculata has started blooming Clarkia unguiculata blooming
 Fig.2. Close up
 As I posted in January, I have lots of Clarkia unguiculata plants, which start blooming the last week in April. Although it seems become early dry season, plants in my yards are still green.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six months later: Native plant garden project 3</title>
      <link>/post/2019/04/17/six-months-later-native-plant-garden-project3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/04/17/six-months-later-native-plant-garden-project3.html</guid>
      <description>Beautiful lupines blooming in my yard! April 2019 lunine blooming
 Native plants have been growing and growing in my yards. In this early spring, lots of lupine plants have been bloomed. As I reported in Jan 16, 2019, our yards have lupine plants from native plant seeds mix. Surprisingly lots of lupine plants grew bigger and had lots of beautiful violet flowers.
 What is this plant? unknown flower</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three months later: Native plant garden project2</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/16/three-months-later-native-plant-garden-project2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/16/three-months-later-native-plant-garden-project2.html</guid>
      <description>Many small plants are growing in my yards. Are they native plants that I sprindkled? As I posted in last fall, I started watering early November 2018 and late rainy season has started after the tragic wild fire (&amp;ldquo;Butte Camp Fire&amp;rdquo;). On January 2019 I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a couple of unfamiliar plants in my yards (Fig. 1), which should be one of native plants in California central valley pollination seed mix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native plant garden project</title>
      <link>/post/2018/10/18/native-plant-garden-project.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/10/18/native-plant-garden-project.html</guid>
      <description>Why don&amp;rsquo;t you grow local native plants in your yards? Lawn in yards are common in USA. However, keeping lawn green needs lots of water in California. California central valley is a center of agriculture due to excellent soil quality (ref). However, weather of California central valley is Mediteranian type, which has long dry summer and wet winter (ref). Recent years California has frequent drought problems (ref), which leads me to try replacing lawn into drought resistant plants, especially local native plants, which are resistant to drought.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>