<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>native-plant on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</title>
    <link>https://knozue.github.io/categories/native-plant.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in native-plant on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://knozue.github.io/categories/native-plant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven months later: Native plant garden project4</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/05/07/seven-months-later-native-plant-garden-project4.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/05/07/seven-months-later-native-plant-garden-project4.html</guid>
      <description> Clarkia unguiculata has started blooming Clarkia unguiculata blooming
 As I posted in January, I have lots of Clarkia unguiculata plants, which start blooming the last week in April. Although it seems become early dry season, plants in my yards are still green.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six months later: Native plant garden project 3</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/04/17/six-months-later-native-plant-garden-project3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2019/04/17/six-months-later-native-plant-garden-project3.html</guid>
      <description>Beautiful lupines blooming in my yard! April 2019 lunine blooming
 Native plants have been growing and growing in my yards. In this early spring, lots of lupine plants have been bloomed. As I reported in Jan 16, 2019, our yards have lupine plants from native plant seeds mix. Surprisingly lots of lupine plants grew bigger and had lots of beautiful violet flowers.
 What is this plant? unknown flower</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native plant garden project</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/18/native-plant-garden-project.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/18/native-plant-garden-project.html</guid>
      <description>Why don&amp;rsquo;t you grow local native plants in your yards? Lawn in yards are common in USA. However, keeping lawn green needs lots of water in California. California central valley is a center of agriculture due to excellent soil quality (ref). However, weather of California central valley is Mediteranian type, which has long dry summer and wet winter (ref). Recent years California has frequent drought problems (ref), which leads me to try replacing lawn into drought resistant plants, especially local native plants, which are resistant to drought.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>