<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>project-management on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</title>
    <link>/categories/project-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in project-management on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/project-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The second solar system project: timeline</title>
      <link>/post/2021/04/04/second-solar-system-project-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021/04/04/second-solar-system-project-timeline/</guid>
      <description>Increasing self-production of electricity at home has a couple of benefits.
 Enhancing decarboniztion (only 29% of electricity from grid was produced from renewable power sources (PGE, 2019)). Increasing independency of power production.  My first solar system produced 3803 kWh per year (an average of 2015 - 2020) 1. Switching a gas-powered car to an electric car in 2019 increased electricity comsumption 2.5 times (from (3938 to 10342 kWh).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make QRcode by R &#43; ggplot2</title>
      <link>/post/2018/09/24/how-to-make-qrcode-by-r-ggplot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/09/24/how-to-make-qrcode-by-r-ggplot2/</guid>
      <description>ggplot2 version of qrcode generator library(qrcode) library(tidyverse) ## ── Attaching packages ─────────────────────────────────────── tidyverse 1.3.0 ── ## ✓ ggplot2 3.3.3 ✓ purrr 0.3.4 ## ✓ tibble 3.0.4 ✓ dplyr 1.0.2 ##</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to read QR code and transfer data to Google sheet</title>
      <link>/post/2018/09/19/how-to-read-qr-code-and-transfer-data-to-google-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/09/19/how-to-read-qr-code-and-transfer-data-to-google-sheet/</guid>
      <description>Copy scanned info by iphone and paste it on your computer software. Universal Clipboard Scan
 Universal Clipboard is useful for this purpose when you use a certain model of iphone, Mac, and macOS.
 Step 1. Install barcode scanner app that can copy scanned info (“QR Scanner”, “QR Reader”, “Qrafter” from App Store worked as of Sep 2018). Step 2. Scan QR code (or any codes?) and copy decoded info.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make QR code in Google Sheet using Integromat.com.</title>
      <link>/post/2018/09/18/how-to-make-qr-code-in-google-sheet-using-integromat-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/09/18/how-to-make-qr-code-in-google-sheet-using-integromat-com/</guid>
      <description>How to make QR code in google sheet using Integromat.com. The goal of this section is to create QRcode in Google Sheet
by using Intergromat.com1!
QRcode generator1a
 Outline Create Integromat.com account (free for 100 MB transfer and/or 1000 operation) Link Integromat.com account to your Google accout (for using Google Driv, Sheet) Create a new Google sheet with “sample”,“url”,“QRcode” columns. Create a new Scenario and run once to test it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>その実験、再現できなければ意味がない</title>
      <link>/post/2018/09/18/%E3%81%9D%E3%81%AE%E5%AE%9F%E9%A8%93%E5%86%8D%E7%8F%BE%E3%81%A7%E3%81%8D%E3%81%AA%E3%81%91%E3%82%8C%E3%81%B0%E6%84%8F%E5%91%B3%E3%81%8C%E3%81%AA%E3%81%84/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/09/18/%E3%81%9D%E3%81%AE%E5%AE%9F%E9%A8%93%E5%86%8D%E7%8F%BE%E3%81%A7%E3%81%8D%E3%81%AA%E3%81%91%E3%82%8C%E3%81%B0%E6%84%8F%E5%91%B3%E3%81%8C%E3%81%AA%E3%81%84/</guid>
      <description>再現できなければ意味がない 数年前、理化学研究所の研究者がNatureに発表した論文が元で1人の自殺者と多額のお金を使った再現性検証実験、多数</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy dad needs project management skills!</title>
      <link>/post/2018/09/12/busy-dad-needs-project-management-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/09/12/busy-dad-needs-project-management-skills/</guid>
      <description>Here I would like to start describe briefly how I manage my work and personal projects.
How to make your experiments reproducible As scientists we need to convince others that your results are not by chance. Here are four advices I want to emphasize here.
 Keep all records on your lab notebook presicely that should be easy to understand. Simplify methods of data input to reduce errors. Have clear and precise data analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
