<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>solar system on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</title>
    <link>https://knozue.github.io/tags/solar-system/</link>
    <description>Recent content in solar system on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://knozue.github.io/tags/solar-system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>En-ROADS, a free web-based climate simulator</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2021/12/15/en-roads-a-free-web-based-climate-simulater/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2021/12/15/en-roads-a-free-web-based-climate-simulater/</guid>
      <description>2021 Nobel prizes for physics 2021 Nobel prizes for physics were awarded to Syukuro Manabe and Klaus Hasselmann for understandig complex systems, and Giorgio Parisi for the physical modelling of Earth&amp;rsquo;s climate. Those areas are very important to understand global warming. After there initial works, we have an web-based interactive application of climate simulation for free, called En-ROADS.
En-ROADS Thanks for introducing En-ROADS in my favorite energy related podcast, The Energy Show (Oct 20, 2021) and an clean energy website article, Cleantechnica.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The second solar system project: timeline</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2021/04/04/second-solar-system-project-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2021/04/04/second-solar-system-project-timeline/</guid>
      <description>Increasing self-production of electricity at home has a couple of benefits.
 Enhancing decarboniztion (only 29% of electricity from grid was produced from renewable power sources (PGE, 2019)). Increasing independency of power production.  My first solar system produced 3803 kWh per year (an average of 2015 - 2020) 1. Switching a gas-powered car to an electric car in 2019 increased electricity comsumption 2.5 times (from (3938 to 10342 kWh).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
