<<<<<<< HEAD
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>publication on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</title>
    <link>/tags/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in publication on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Another plant defense hormone is required for responses to light in plant</title>
      <link>/post/2018/10/26/another-plant-defense-hormone-is-required-for-responses-to-light-in-plant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/10/26/another-plant-defense-hormone-is-required-for-responses-to-light-in-plant/</guid>
      <description>Plants use light as energy source as well as signals for environmental signal changes. Under the canopy shade phtosynthesis activity is reduced, therefore plants responded to existance of neighboring plants that causes near future crisis, such as growing taller and flowering earlier to produce seeds as early as possible, which are collectivcey known as shade avoidance responses. This week I published my paper titled “Network analysis reveals a role for salicylic acid pathway components in shade avoidance” in Plant Physiology, an international journal in plant biology.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
=======
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>publication on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</title>
    <link>https://knozue.github.io/tags/publication.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in publication on Daddy&#39;s data analysis by Kazu Nozue</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://knozue.github.io/tags/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Another plant defense hormone is required for responses to light in plant</title>
      <link>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/26/another-plant-defense-hormone-is-required-for-responses-to-light-in-plant.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knozue.github.io/post/2018/10/26/another-plant-defense-hormone-is-required-for-responses-to-light-in-plant.html</guid>
      <description>Plants use light as energy source as well as signals for environmental signal changes. Under the canopy shade phtosynthesis activity is reduced, therefore plants responded to existance of neighboring plants that causes near future crisis, such as growing taller and flowering earlier to produce seeds as early as possible, which are collectivcey known as shade avoidance responses. This week I published my paper titled &amp;ldquo;Network analysis reveals a role for salicylic acid pathway components in shade avoidance&amp;rdquo; in Plant Physiology, an international journal in plant biology.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
>>>>>>> 164dea5f37d550e6f069a45716c319aa1f4b62b6
